<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>New Zealand on Taubin dot CC</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/new-zealand/</link>
    <description>Recent content in New Zealand on Taubin dot CC</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2020 - 2025 Dusty</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/new-zealand/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Budget 2019 I Was Wrong</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/budget-2019-i-was-wrong/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/budget-2019-i-was-wrong/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&#34;https://unsplash.com/@neonbrand?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&#34;&gt;NeONBRAND&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;https://unsplash.com/search/photos/mistake?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&#34;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I admit it, I was wrong. In my &lt;a href=&#34;__GHOST_URL__/2019/05/29/2019-nz-budget/&#34;&gt;last post&lt;/a&gt;, I wrote about how in-probable it was that the 2019 NZ Budget hack was just due to someone using the search engine on the website. Well I was wrong. I had expected the IT team at the NZ Treasury to have at least a little bit of competence. Sadly the seem to be &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rnz.co.nz/news/political/390846/budget-breach-didn-t-break-the-law-treasury&#34;&gt;incredibly incompetent&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hack at the Treasury was in fact due to someone searching for the document, and finding it. I am utterly flabbergasted at how the Treasury department handled everything to do with this. Now this certainly does not absolve National of their handling of everything either, but again I am not political and I’m not going to get into that.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2019 NZ Budget</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2019-nz-budget/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2019-nz-budget/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;There has been a whole lot happening here in NZ in the past 24 or so hours. You see the 2019 budget for NZ is meant to be released tomorrow (Thursday), but was apparently leaked by the opposition party on Tuesday. This has led to a lot of speculation, name calling, threats, police reports, etc… You know typical politics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now normally I wouldn’t care about this at all, and certainly wouldn’t write about it here. The thing is, anyone that knows me knows I don’t really care for politics. I never discuss it and don’t follow any of the parties. That said I do vote, but not even my wife knows (or cares) who I vote for.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
